Frances Fox Piven Papers, 1957-2011
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. TEACHING, 1963-
  - Columbia University
    - Administration
      - Campus activism: "The Siege of Columbia, " 1968-69, n.d.
        - Articles and clippings, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Institutional responses, 1968-69 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - Printed materials, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Reports and papers
        - Class rank and selective service, circa 1967-68 [includes unpublished paper, Allan Silver, "Politics and the Recreation of Columbia University," 1968] (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Paul Nyden, "Unions and Unionization Attempts at Columbia University," 1967 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Columbia University published reports, 1967, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Descriptions of the Urban Planning Program, 1973-75 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Course materials
      - Evaluations, 1965-71 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Class rosters, 1977-78 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - "Analysis of Policy Formation": syllabus, exams, and reserve list, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - "Community Organizing in the Urban Social Service System": prospectus and reading lists, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - "The Future of American Housing Policy" (Architecture 4415): correspondence and Piven's Paper, "The Government's Role in Housing," 1977 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "Politics of Social Welfare": outlines, memos, exams, reading lists, notes, and clippings, 1966-72 (Box 28, Folder 10-15)
      - "Social Planning": notes and reading lists, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "Social Work and Social Problems": memo, notes, and articles, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "The Structures of the Urban Community": lecture outline, reading list, and exam, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified
        - "CO4 Reprints": reprints and lecture notes, circa 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - "CO3" and "CO4" final lecture notes, 1969, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - "404": notes, clippings, papers and articles, circa 1968-72
          - "Education" (Box 29, Folder 6)
          - "Health" (Box 29, Folder 7)
          - "Housing" (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
          - "The University" (Box 29, Folder 10)
          - "Welfare" (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - "A Study of Squatting" (collection of student essays supervised by Piven, circa 1971) (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
  - Boston University
    - Correspondence
      - 1971-82, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1-13)
      - Students, 1976-81 (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Troy Armstrong, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - Cynthia Hamilton, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 16)
        - Andrew "Chip" Maxwell, 1977-79 (Box 31, Folder 17)
        - Eric Schneider, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 18)
        - Richard W. Sterling, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 19)
        - John Tirman, 1978-80 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Carol McClung Mueller: proposals and correspondence regarding her study of ERA activists and the women's movement, 1979-80 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Open Enrollment Program
      - Sam Bass Warner: correspondence, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - General (includes proposals), 1973-75 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Silber controversy
      - Clippings, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Board of Trustees, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Course materials
      - General reading lists and syllabi, circa 1970-80 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - "Big City Politics" (P.O. 511)
        - Syllabi and reading lists, lecture notes, exams, and evaluations, 1973-81 (Box 32, Folder 6)
        - Subject/lecture notes, clippings and reports, ca. 1977
          - Decentralization (Box 32, Folder 7)
          - Fiscal crisis (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - "The Changing Structure of American Government" (P.O. 606)
        - Syllabus, clippings, and notes, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Collected articles and unpublished papers (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - Student paper proposals (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - "Movements of the Poor" (P.O. 625): syllabus, lecture notes, and exams, 1974-80 (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
      - "The Politics of Social Welfare" (P.O. 509): syllabi, exams, notes and rosters, 1974-1981 (Box 33, Folder 5-7)
        - Articles, clippings, and research notes, 1971-81 (Box 33, Folder 8)
        - Lecture notes and subject files, 1975-82
          - Education (Box 33, Folder 9)
          - Health (Box 33, Folder 10-11)
          - Housing (Box 34, Folder 1)
          - The University (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - "The Politics of Social Welfare" (P.O. 549/509): Syllabus, exams, and lecture notes, circa 1972-78 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Subject/lecture notes, 509 & 707, circa 1972-78
        - "The Great Society" (Box 34, Folder 4)
        - Income maintenance (Box 34, Folder 5)
        - Urban crisis (Box 34, Folder 6)
        - Housing (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - "Urban Political Issues": syllabi, exams, lecture notes, and student roster, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - City University of New York
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1984, 1996-97 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - From Bologna, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Brian Guerre, 1984-89 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Richard Hofrichter, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Administration
      - Class rosters, 1994, 1996-97 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Committees
        - Colloquium: correspondence, 1983-86 (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Curriculum: memoranda, 1982-85 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        - Rutgers-Newark evaluation: correspondence, notes, memoranda, and curricula vitae, 1985-86 (Box 35, Folder 6)
        - Search, 1985-86 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Rockefeller Foundation grant, "Evaluating...Voter Registration Systems..."
        - Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 35, Folder 8)
        - Financial materials, 1992-93 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - City University of New York Political Science Conference: notes, memoranda, and printed material, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - "3rd Exams": correspondence and memoranda, 1983-91 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Campus activism
      - Graduate Faculty for a CUNY Future: memoranda, notes, and correspondence, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - CUNY strike: notes and research materials, 1990 [includes manuscript by Piven, "What Did the Students Accomplish?"] (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - CUNY Hearings: correspondence and research materials, circa 1990 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Equal Protection lawsuit: correspondence, memoranda, legal materials, and clippings, 1991-96 (Box 36, Folder 6-9)
  - Visiting professorships and sabbaticals
    - Brooklyn College, 1975-76
      - Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Administration
        - Teaching evaluations (Box 37, Folder 2)
        - Class rosters and grade sheets (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Course materials
        - Albany tutorials: correspondence (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - "Big City Politics": syllabi and course materials (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - Fieldwork seminar: syllabus, notes, programs, and correspondence (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - Greenpoint campus course: notes, syllabus, and exams (Box 37, Folder 7)
        - "Metropolitan Legal Structure": notes, articles, and unpublished materials (Box 37, Folder 8)
        - Political Science 731 and 734: notes, syllabus and exams (Box 37, Folder 9)
        - Student writings: correspondence and exams (Box 37, Folder 10)
        - Syllabi and course descriptions (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - New York University Law School
      - "New Perspectives on 'Deviant' Behavior": course proposal and notes, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Sabbatical contacts (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - University of Amsterdam: correspondence and lectures, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 15-16)
    - Institute for Advanced Studies: correspondence and report, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 17)
- SERIES IV. COMMUNITY SERVICE (circa 1964- )
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - Board of Directors
      - Correspondence, 1977-88 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Memoranda, 1978-86 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - General correspondence, 1972-88, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Committees
      - Ad hoc group on Reagan budget cuts: report, 1981-82 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Biennial Resolution No. 2/The Right to Work (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Constitutional Rights and Economic Benefits (CREB), 1978-79 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Poverty and Constitutional Rights
        - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes and reports, 1981-90 (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
        - Correspondence with Robert Collins on homelessness, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - Meeting materials, Oct 1987 and Mar 1989 (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
        - Policy #318: reports and memoranda, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Poverty Think Tank, Sep 1987 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Poverty and Civil Liberties
        - Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and reports, 1983-88 (Box 40, Folder 1-3)
        - Policy #317: "Poverty and Civil Liberties" (Box 40, Folder 4)
        - Ad hoc Committee on Children's Rights (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Equality
        - Discussions of economic rights, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - Memoranda, 1973, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Economic Rights, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Medicaid Task Force, 1983-84 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - American Political Science Association
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1975-85 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Program Committee, 1975-76 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
    - Conference Program, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - American Sociological Association Meeting: correspondence, program, and notes, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Association for Community Organization Now (ACORN), 1979-81 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - American Poverty Law Educational Foundation: correspondence and memoranda, 1983-84 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Basic Systems: program, correspondence, and budget materials, 1965-66 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Blackside, Inc.
    - "America's War on Poverty": correspondence and proposal, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Eyes on the Prize": correspondence, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Campaign for Media Fairness on Welfare: correspondence, memoranda, financial records, and publicity materials, 1991-96, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
  - Caucus for a New Political Science
    - Correspondence, 1974-75 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Notes and memoranda re: election, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - New Political Science editorial board: correspondence, 1976-82 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Cavtat Round Table, "Socialism and the Economy," 1986 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Center for Philadelphia Studies, circa 1982
    - Correspondence and "A Philadelphia Prospectus, circa 1982" (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - National Consultants Comments [includes Piven's "Health and Human Services Task Force Interim Report"] (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Citizen Involvement Network: correspondence, 1975 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Coalition for Basic Human Needs: correspondence, testimony, and public relations materials, circa 1979 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Coalition on Human Needs
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Funding proposals, 1994-95 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Committee of 100: correspondence, memoranda, and printed material, 1995-97 (Box 43, Folder 7-9)
  - Community Action Network Program: memo to advisory committee, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Community Service Society: preliminary draft of task force report, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Congress of Racial Equality: paper by Floyd McKissick, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Socialists of America (Box 44)
    (see boxes 45 and 46)
  - Downtown Welfare Advocacy Center: notes and memoranda, 1981-82 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Farmworkers Justice Fund: correspondence, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Firing Line: "Resolved: Welfare Has Done More Harm Than Good": notes, correspondence, and research materials, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    [see also video cassette, SERIES VIII,--AUDIOVISUAL), 1994]
  - Flint Sit-Down Project: correspondence, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Ford Foundation: correspondence, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Hotel Tenants Rights Project: correspondence and reports, 1988-89 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - HumanSERVE (Box 44)
    (see boxes 46-52)
  - Institute for Labor and Mental Health, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Institute for Labor Education and Research
    - Correspondence, 1976-79 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Position papers, proposals, and assorted manuscripts, circa 1976-77 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Funding proposal, Jan 1977 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Institute for New Communications roundtables, "Building a Feminist Economic Program," 1983-84: proposal, correspondenceand memoranda, minutes and proceedings, and final report (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Institute for Policy Research: 19?? (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Institute for Policy Studies: paper by Piven and Cloward, "The Reagan Attack on the Welfare State," with comments by Marc Raskin, and news release regarding conference, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Institute for Public Policy Research: unpublished. manuscript. by Gosta Esping-Anderson, "Equality and Work in the Post-Industrial Life Cycle," and Piven's commentary, for Reinventing the Left, circa 1993-94 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Democratic Socialists of America
    - Constitutions and amendments, circa. 1985 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence, memoranda and reports
      - 1983-88 (Box 45, Folder 2-8)
      - 1989-93 (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
    - Convention packet and publications, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
    - National Executive Committee meeting materials, 17-18 Sep 1988 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - National Board meeting materials, 11-13 Nov 1988 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Responses to the death of Michael Harrington, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - HumanSERVE
    - General correspondence and memoranda
      - 1983-86 [includes Paul Wellstone, 1984] (Box 46, Folder 8-12)
      - 1986-89 (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
    - National Staff meeting and mailings
      - 1986 (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
      - 1987-88 (Box 48, Folder 1-7)
    - NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, 1987, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Voter registration
      - Data and research materials (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Clippings on voter registration and turnout, 1982-89 (Box 49, Folder 1-6)
      - Information kits for service agencies, 1987, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Proposals
      - Program proposals, 1985-89 (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
      - "Universal Enfranchisement: A National Advocacy and Public Education Campaign," 1986-87 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Public relations materials and poster (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Newsletters and press releases, circa. 1985 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Senate testimony, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - State registration initiatives
      - Litigation campaign, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - California, 1986
        - General (Box 50, Folder 2)
        - Briefs, HumanSERVE (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Briefs, government response (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Clippings (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Florida, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - New Jersey, circa 1986 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Texas, circa 1985-89 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Strategy Conference for Full Political Participation: agendas, reports, and memoranda, Sep 1985 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Reports, articles, and publications
      - Articles, 1984-89 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Reports and surveys, 1985-88 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Undated materials (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - ABC News Report, "The 1982 Vote" (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Cloward and Piven, unpublished. manuscript, "Rising Turnout Decisive in 1984" (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - "Enhancing the Voter Participation of Traditionally Underrepresented Groups," Aug, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - "On Gerrymandering," UCLA Law Review, Oct 1985 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - "Non-Voter Study, '85-'86," Ford Foundation, Apr 1987 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - "Winning the South in 1992: A New Analysis of the 1988 Presidential Election" (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Drafts of unidentified manuscript by Piven and Cloward, 1986, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Institute for the Study of Socialism and Democracy: correspondence and brochure, 1983-84 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Institute for Research on Poverty, 1976-80 (Box 51, Folder 9-10)
  - International Journal of Urban and Regional Research, 1976-84 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - International League for Rights and Liberation of Peoples
    - circa 1977-84 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - circa. 1988 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - International Political Science Association World Congress, Berlin, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - International Sociological Association: Committee of Poverty, Social Welfare and Social Policy meeting, Budapest, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - International Sociological Association World Congress, Mexico City, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - International Sociological Association World Congress, Madrid, 1990 (re: Piven's panel: "Women and the Welfare State") (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - International Sociological Association World Congress, Bielefeld, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Jefferson Center for New Democratic Processes: correspondence, printed material, and reports, "Policy Jury on School-Based Clinics" (Minnesota) and "The St. Paul Mayoral Election," circa 1988 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - League of Women Voters for New York State, "CampaignWatch 1992": correspondence, press reports, press materials and reports, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - "Making Contact," "Welfare Reform and the Rural Poor," National Radio Project, 1996 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Mental Health Problems Review Committee, Department. of Health, Education and Welfare: correspondence, memoranda, and reports on grant applications, 1975-79 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Metroview, "Welfare Reform: Scapegoating Women," Mar 1994 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - MIT Visiting Committee: correspondence and memoranda, 1981-82 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Mobilization for Youth (Box 53)
    (see boxes 55-61)
  - National Student Action Union: correspondence, conference agenda, and budget proposal, 1989-90 [includes paper, "Organizing the Emerging Student Movement: General Principles and Organization, Strategy and Tactics"] (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - National Union of the Homeless: correspondence and clippings, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - National Welfare Rights Organization
    - Publicity materials and proposal, circa 1966 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Printed materials, 1970-72 [including Hilary Rose, "Bread and Justice: the National Welfare Rights Organization," reprint, The Sociological Review Monograph, 1975] (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - 2nd National Conference materials, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Convention materials, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - NOW Commission, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Pacific Streets Productions
    - Correspondence, 1979-80 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Proposal, "The Law, the Courts, and the People," 1982 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - "The Law and Sexual Freedom": outline and related correspondence, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Policy Alternatives for the Caribbean and Central America (Box 54)
    (see box 62)
  - Policy Studies Organization, 1982-88 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)
  - "The Political Economy of Inflation and Unemployment," conference, Williams College, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - "Popular Power in Post-Industrial Society," CUNY Conference (Box 54)
    (see boxes 63, 63a, and 63b)
  - Poverty/Rights Action Center: reports and publicity materials, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - "Reconstructive Knowledge," conference, Hampshire College: correspondence, and papers, circa 1979 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Smith College, "Project on Women and Social Change": correspondence, 1978-82 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Mobilization for Youth
    - Administration
      - General, 1963-66 [includes June Meyer (Jordan) letter] (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Minutes
        - December Meeting No. II, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 2)
        - Meeting of the Head Workers, May 1963 (Box 55, Folder 3)
        - Meetings called by city administrator, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Congressional testimony, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Congressional hearing transcripts, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Publicity and community relations
      - Early history: notes and documents [includes timeline] (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - MFY publicity, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - "Organizational Strains": reports, memoranda, and correspondence pertaining to criticism of MFY, 1963-64 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Clippings and public relations material responding to criticism, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Speeches and statements, 1963-65 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Programs
      - General policy announcements, papers and memoranda, circa 1961-63 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - General program material, 1962-63 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Board of Education: correspondence and memoranda, 1963-64 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Civil Rights movement activities, 1963-64 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Community Organization Staff: minutes and memoranda, 1962-64 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Housing Program: statements, circa 1961-66 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Legal Services Unit, 1964-65 (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Voter Registration Campaign, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Work Program: notes, clippings, and annual report, 1963-64 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Research
      - Research staff meeting minutes and memoranda, 1962-63 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Juvenile delinquency: summary and proposal regarding research by Raymond Gould, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Lloyd E. Ohlin: writings, 1957-64 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Opiate addiction: correspondence and writings by Isidor Chein, 1959 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      - NIMH Research reports, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 5)
      - "An Exploratory Study of Voluntary Associations of the Lower East Side," May, 1961 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - "Five Decades of Action for Children: A History of the Children's Bureau" (Washington: U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1962) (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - "Report to the President," President's Committee on Juvenile Delinquency and Youth Crime, May 1962 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - "The Lower East Side Story: Emphasizing the Mobilization Area," Sep 1962 (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - "Training in Parent and Neighborhood Leadership Toward the Prevention and Control of Juvenile Delinquency," In Service Training Dept., NYC Youth Board, 1962-63 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - Research Center, Columbia University School of Social Work (CUSSW), "Research Program for Mobilization For Youth," circa 1964 (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - "Master Annotated Bibliography of the Papers of Mobilization for Youth" (published, unpublished and presented at conferences) 1965 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - "Who Was Reached?: An Analysis of the Population Served by Mobilization for Youth, 1962-5" by Stephen Leeds, CUSSW (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - "Notes from the Ghetto: Papers from the MFY Experience," July 1966 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - "A Review of Research in conjunction with Mobilization for Youth," CUSSW, January 1967 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Fundraising
      - Department of Health, Education and Welfare
        - Application for Demonstration Grant, May 1965 (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - Demonstration Projects Technical Advisory Panel: minutes, 1962-63 (Box 58, Folder 4-6)
      - Ford Foundation, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - National Institute of Mental Health
        - Children's Bureau-Delinquency Committee: transcripts of proceedings, 1959 (Box 58, Folder 8)
        - Reports to the Congress on Juvenile Delinquency, prepared by the NIMH and Children's Bureau, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Appendices, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 10)
        - Site visits, 1959-65 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      - Proposals, 1957-59, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1-7)
      - "President's Committee on Juvenile Delinquency and Youth Crime": report, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Interviews (Box 60-61)
  - Policy Alternatives for the Caribbean and Central America (PACCA)
    - Correspondence, 1985-87, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1-2)